<book title="Minecolonies Resurrection" cover="gbook:default" fontSize="0.6">

    <include ref="gbook:xml/standard.xml"/>

    <chapter id="Welcome">

        <page>
            <space height="5%"/>
            <image src="gbook:header" tw="190" th="30"/>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p space="0" align="center">Guidebook</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center">IT'S NOT UPDATED, but still good</p>
            <p align="center">Wait for the new wiki to be released</p>
            <p></p>
            <p space="6" align="center">__________</p>
            <p></p>
            <image src="gbook:WissiFull" x="60" y="4" tw="60" th="132"/>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#1aa3ff" indent="45">by:</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Welcome to Minecolonies</title>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#0004ff">A complete version of the documentation is available here:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link indent="48" href="https://wiki.minecolonies.ldtteam.com/">Official WIKI</link>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p>MineColonies is a Colony/Town Simulator that adds many structures and NPC workers and guards that you control and put to work for you! Based around a townhall and
                village mechanics, there are numerous workers that can be added to your colony, building a busy and vibrant Village/Town/City/Metropolis within Minecraft. There is
                no coded limit to the number of NPC’s at your disposal, so you can create a small efficient Village dedicated to a particular type of worker, or a sprawling
                metropolis with many type os workers. It’s entirely up to you!
            </p>
        </page>

        <page id="Index">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Minecolonies Index</p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Tut">&#9769; Tutorial</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Tut:SSSC">&#9760; Supply Ship - Supply Camp</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Tut:TH">&#9760; Town Hall</link>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Workers">&#9769; Workers</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Workers:LVLUP">&#9760; Level Up system</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Workers:TOOLLVL">&#9760; Tool Level</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Workers:Traits">&#9760; Traits</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Workers:JobDesc">&#9760; Job Descriptions</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Workers:Happ">&#9760; Happiness System</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Workers:Builder">&#9755; Builder</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Workers:Farmer">&#9755; Farmer</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Workers:Lumberjack">&#9755; Lumberjack</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Workers:Miner">&#9755; Miner</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Workers:Fisherman">&#9755; Fisherman</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Workers:Guard">&#9755; Guard</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Workers:D-man">&#9755; Deliveryman</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Workers:Baker">&#9755; Baker</link>
        </page>

        <page>
            <link ref="Build">&#9769; Buildings</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Build:SS">&#9760; Supply Ship</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Build:SC">&#9760; Supply Camp</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Tut:TH">&#9760; Town Hall</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Build:CH">&#9760; Citizen Hut</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Build:WH">&#9760; Warehouse</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Build:WP">&#9755; Waypoint System</link>
            <link indent="24" ref="Build:Path">&#9755; Path System</link>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Schem">&#9769; Schematics</link>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Recipe">&#9769; Recipes</link>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Command">&#9769; Player Commands</link>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#1aa3ff" align="center">____________________________</p>
            <p></p>
            <link indent="24" href="https://wiki.minecolonies.ldtteam.com/">&#9753; Official WIKI</link>
            <link indent="24" href="http://www.minecolonies.com/">&#9753; Official Website</link>
            <link indent="24" href="https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/minecolonies">&#9753; CurseForge</link>
            <link indent="24" href="https://discord.gg/XuUTu46">&#9753; Discord</link>
            <link indent="24" href="https://github.com/Minecolonies/minecolonies">&#9753; Github</link>
            <link indent="24" href="https://www.patreon.com/Minecolonies">&#9753; Become a Patreon</link>
        </page>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="Tut">

        <page id="SSSC">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Tutorial</p>
            <p>CONGRATULATIONS! You are ready to embark on an adventure to explore, conquer and establish your own Settlement. Work hard and turn it into a thriving Town. Hone your
                Leader skills and grow grow grow into a City. Lastly… can you be a grand leader and finally achieve a Metropolis??? (Check your ingame Minecolonies Achievements)
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The first thing you want to do is find the perfect spot to settle down. Before you do that, there are two things you have to consider. They are the most important
                thing you should read and consider to ensure a successful Town and avoid frustration. Read all considerations first, before placing your Supply Ship, Supply Camp or
                even starting to play:
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>1: Supply Ship/Camp Placement.</p>
            <p>2: Town Hall placement</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>1: Supply Ship/Camp Placement.</title>
            <p>When you place the Supply Ship it spawns a chest on the exact block you right clicked, that contains a Town Hall block and a Building Tool. To place the Supply Ship,
                you need to have a large enough body of water. Supply Ship is 32 x 11 blocks in length and width. The recommended size of water must be at least (32 x 20). The
                Chest will be directly in front of the ladder to board the Supply Ship (8 blocks from the boarding ladder) and the ladder is not in the middle of the Supply Ship.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#DF0000" align="center" underline="true">Once the Supply Ship is placed, you can't place another in this World anymore.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: if you can't place the Supply Ship, try block by block: to the right, left, closer of further from the water, or even directly over water, creating a walkway
                block by block).
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>When you place the Supply Camp it will spawn a chest that will contain the Town Hall block and the Building Tool. To place the Supply Camp, you need to have a large
                enough flat, clear piece of land. The recommended flat piece of land must be at least 16 x 17 blocks in size. When you place the Supply Camp a chest will appear on
                the exact block you right clicked. But please take into account the Town Hall placement as well before you place your Supply Camp.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#DF0000" align="center" underline="true">Once the Supply Ship is placed, you can't place another Ship or Camp in this World anymore.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>(Hint: if you’re not being able to place the Supply Camp, try it block by block to the right, left, closer of further from the area you cleared. It can not contain
                any holes or have any flowers, grass, fens, etc. Must be completely flat and clear.)
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>2: Town Hall placement</title>
            <p>The protected area of your Colony (once the Town Hall has been placed) will be 200 block radius, first palcement of your Town Hall block. Plan carefully where to
                place your Town Hall. 200 blocks in every direction will be your Town's protected area including ANY world generated structures from bedrock to the sky limit.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Note: You can configure your own Town area radius (for SSP worlds) in the minecolonies.cfg file inside the "../minecraft/config/" folder of your own world.</p>
            <link align="center" href="https://wiki.minecolonies.com/wiki/18/server">WIKI config section</link>
            <p></p>
            <p>Due to the protected area of each Town, scout carefully your surroundings to make sure you are clear of any other Towns nearby preventing you from placing your Town
                Hall. If there is another Colony too close to your current position you won’t be able to place a Town Hall.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>To know if there is a colony close to your current position. We included information in the debug screen (press F3 button). A real time tracker showing you the
                distance to nearest colony, the colony you’re currently in or if there is no colony close at all. If there is a colony close to your current position, the required
                distance to place your Town Hall.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>For example, in the official Minecolonies server it will be 200 + 20 = 220 (area of each Town + empty blocks between Towns = Total blocks required). It will say:
                “Next colony is XXX blocks away. (420 required to place a Colony).”
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The minimum distance from a Town to safely place your Town hall in the Official Minecolonies Server will be 420 blocks. Your Town area + buffer space + other
                player’s Town area. (200 + 20 + 200 = 420). 420 blocks from other players’ Town center to Your Town center.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p bold="true">After exploring, thinking and planning carefully, you found the perfect spot to start your Town. There are 3 steps to start your Colony:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Step 1. Craft your Supply Ship or Supply Camp and place it.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Step 2. Use Building Tool to place your Town Hall .</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Step 3. Craft the Builder’s Hut block and use the Building Tool to place.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>These are the steps to start using the mod and get you on your way to create your Colony. From this point on, you should be able to “place”, “build”, “upgrade” and
                “manage” all your buildings and Citizens.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p underline="true">Lets look at each step in detail:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Step 1. Craft your Supply Ship or Supply Camp. Now place it by right clicking a block with it. Your Supply Ship or Supply Camp will spawn (which you can use as
                shelter, warehouse or even as materials to give to your builder). It will also spawn a chest with your Town Hall block and the Building Tool. (You can watch this
                video from our youtube channel about how to use the Building Tool to position all your buildings).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <link align="center" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gz1I7hhMd5Y">The Building Tool</link>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: Meanwhile, gather as much materials as possible to be able to give them to your builder when he starts building. He will be asking you for all kinds of
                materials he will need for each building or upgrade. Mainly oak wood, cobblestone and torches for the starter builds. Further upgrades will require more elaborate
                materials.
            </p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page id="TH">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center">Town Hall</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Step 2. After you have carefully decided where you want to place your Town Hall (Remember, the position where you place the Town Hall block will be the center of
                your Town’s protected area. Once placed, the area will be set and cannot be changed), use your Building Tool to place the Town Hall block, once you “commit” to the
                placement of the Town Hall, the Town Hall block will be set as well as your Town's protected area and your Citizens will automagically appear.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now, you can right click the Town Hall block to look at its GUI (graphical user interface).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Tabs on the left side of GUI are:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Information.-This will give you some statistics about your citizens and workers.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Actions.-This is the most important tab. You are able to see your Towns name and various Buttons here:</p>
            <p indent="8">- Build Town Hall (also upgrades it)</p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Town Hall (in case it gets “accidentally” modified)</p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Citizens (not implemented yet)</p>
            <p indent="8">- Toggle Specialization (future use)</p>
            <p indent="8">- Rename Colony (if you want a different name)</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Permissions.-Here you can see the Owner and other players invited to your Town to collaborate. You can add a player and give him a status in your Town. Each status
                will have certain privileges in the protection system.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Citizens.-Just the names of the Citizens. Your npc citizens, not players.</p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Settings.- You may set it automatic hiring mode or Manual mode. Every time a building is finished and you have an unemployed citizen, he may be automatically
                assigned or you can manually assign him according to his "Traits".
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Work Orders.-Here you will see the work orders the Builder has in the order they have been assigned. The builder will not start another order until he has
                successfully completed the top one. Here you can delete any build order he has or change their priorities. When you delete a work order which is currently being
                built the builder will stop building and only continue when you assign him to this building again.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Step 3. Before any building can be built, you have to craft the “builder’s hut” block in the crafting table and use your Building Tool to place his hut. Once you
                “commit” to the placement of the builder’s hut, the block will be placed and the builder will be automatically assigned (or you can manually assign one with the
                best "traits" for builder if you changed this in the settings tab in the Town Hall’s GUI).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <title>You now officially have a &quot;Builder!&quot; CONGRATULATIONS!</title>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you can access the Builder’s hut block, right click on it for the GUI and it's options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Header: The Worker assigned and his Skill Level. (you level him up by assigning more build/upgrade/repair tasks. The higher the level the faster and more efficient
                he/she will be).
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If builder gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- to create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Now issue the builder the &quot;Build&quot; assignment so he can build his own Hut first. Without the builder’s hut being built, the builder cannot build any other
                buildings. He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to check the &quot;chat&quot; regularly to see what materials the builder is requesting for
                any build/upgrade.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see builder has not finished a work order and you don’t see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder’s hut and &quot;recall&quot; the
                builder and wait a bit to see what he/she needs. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there any materials that are required and he might be missing,
                they will be in red.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Consider &quot;Upgrading&quot; the Builder’s hut to level 2 as soon as you can so he may be able to upgrade any other building. Builder can only build other
                buildings up to his huts level.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>You have now done the most important steps to start and create your Colony.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Once the builder has finished his Hut, you're ready to start building ANY other building you want. Just craft the desired block and use your building tool to place
                the desired building and go into the GUI for that new block you just placed, right click on it and click on the &quot;Build&quot; button. That simple!
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>From this point on, you should be able to &quot;place&quot;, &quot;build&quot;, &quot;upgrade&quot; and &quot;manage&quot; all your buildings and Citizens.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Your questions is probably what to build next? The Miner, Sawmill, Farmer, Fisherman, Guard, Deliveryman, Warehouse? But you start with only 4 citizens! The next
                step is to plan and place the &quot;Citizen Hut&quot;. This will give you one Citizen for each level of &quot;Citizen Hut&quot; you build in your Town! That’s
                crazy, right?
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Now what do you do with so many Citizens? You cannot assign more than 1 worker per building. Therefore, consider building additional buildings. (more miners,
                lumberjacks, builders, farmers, fishermen... and more to come!). Check the Citizen Hut section for more detailed info.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: Upgrade your buildings to the highest level each one has to unlock achievements and to enable your worker access special features.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="Workers">

        <page id="LVLUP">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Information about each worker.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#DF0000" align="center" underline="true">Rainy weather will make your citizens stop working!!!</p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Level Up System</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>There is a system in place for how the workers &quot;Level Up&quot;. The level of their building is what will put a limit on the &quot;Worker Level&quot; he/she can
                achieve. Every time you level up their building, the worker's max level limit will be DOUBLE the previous limit! Currently there is NO limit on the Workers &quot;Skill
                Level&quot; (once you have made his building level 5, of course).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8" underline="true">Building Level Max Worker Level</p>
            <p indent="32">0 2</p>
            <p indent="32">1 4</p>
            <p indent="32">2 8</p>
            <p indent="32">3 16</p>
            <p indent="32">4 32</p>
            <p indent="32">5 - -</p>
        </page>

        <page id="TOOLLVL">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Tool Leveling System</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>There is also a system in place for the type of tools the workers can use depending on the level of their building. The level of their building is what will put a
                limit on the "Tool Level" the worker will be able to use. Every time you level up their building, the level of the tool the worker can use will increase.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p underline="true">Building Level Max Tool Level</p>
            <p indent="8">0 Wood w/mining level: Stone</p>
            <p indent="8">1 Stone w/mining level: Iron</p>
            <p indent="8">2 Iron w/mining level: Diamond</p>
            <p indent="8">3 Diamond w/mining level: Obsidian</p>
            <p indent="8">4 Any w/mining level Cobalt</p>
            <p indent="8">5 Any w/any Enchants</p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page id="Traits">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Traits</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>When you click on the "Hire" button, you will see a list of the available workers and the best "Traits" for the specific worker you are hiring will be in green
                (primary) and yellow (secondary) to help you decide which is the best worker for hire. There is a Formula for this:
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" underline="true">Primary Trait*2 + Secondary Trait*1 = Rate of Level Up.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>For example; If Intelligence is Primary (green colored) and Endurance Secondary (yellow colored) and the worker assigned has Intelligence "2" and Endurance "4" that
                is (2x2)+(4x1) = 8. That means that this worker will be able to level up 8 times faster
            </p>
        </page>

        <page id="JobDesc">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Job Descriptions</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Next to each Worker are the best "Traits" for each one to have in order for them to work faster, more efficiently and also they will "level Up" at a faster rate.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p underline="true">Job Description Best Traits</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Builder Intelligence &amp; Strength</p>
            <p>Farmer Endurance &amp; Charisma</p>
            <p>Lumberjack Strength &amp; Charisma</p>
            <p>Miner Strength &amp; Endurance</p>
            <p>Fisherman Intelligence &amp; Dexterity</p>
            <p>Guard Intelligence &amp; Strength</p>
            <p>Deliveryman Intelligence &amp; Endurance</p>
            <p></p>
            <image src="gbook:Traits" tw="180" th="33"/>
        </page>

        <page id="Happ">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Saturation and Happiness</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Saturation and Happiness system for the Citizens are locked in one to the other. Which means that the Citizens require food (just like the player does) to be
                able to Work. The Citizens however will NOT die if their saturation goes down to 0, they will simply stop leveling anymore and will also request food in chat
                regularly as well as have slowness slowness effect. The Workers will stop working. This will also affect the overall happiness of each Citizen a well as the entire
                Town.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>There is an overall colony happiness + individual worker happiness:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Overall colony happiness is between 1-10 (initially set to 5)</p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Happiness depends on several factors; security, housing and saturation.</title>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Every night there is a recalculation of the happiness based on the following:</p>
            <p>- If average colonist saturation is greater than 5 (+0.1 per level) if it's less than 5 (-0.1 per level).</p>
            <p>- If average colonist housing is greater than 1 (+0.1 per level)</p>
            <p>- If 1 guard level exists for each worker level (worker level 5 needs guard level 5 (hut))</p>
            <p>+ 0.1 for each average level more -0.1 for each average worker less.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>* Each time a citizen is killed by a player it will decerease by -9 (Reset to lowest level = 1)</p>
            <p>* Each natural death of a citizen it will decrease by -1.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Currently, their skills have NO level cap at all.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">The Citizen Hunger System:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Citizen hunger system is between 0-10.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>* On 0 = no leveling anymore + he requests food in chat regularly + slowness effect. Workere stops working.</p>
            <p>* On less than 3 = no healing and -25% leveling speed.</p>
            <p>* Between 3 and 5 = - 10% leveling speed.</p>
            <p>* Between 5 and 7 = + 10% leveling speed.</p>
            <p>* Between 7 and 10 = + 25% leveling speed.</p>
            <p>* On 10 = double healing speed +25% leveling speed.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>They refresh their saturation by eating, just like the player.</p>
            <p>Saturation is displayed with the saturation bar in the citizen's GUI.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>When they go to sleep, saturation will decrease by 0.2 * worker hut level.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>When they get home they search their chest for food and eat it if they have less than 10 in saturation.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Deliveryman will not remove any type of food there is in the citizens' hut chests.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>If the citizen has a happiness less than 7, the citizen will check his personal inventory and his own hut chest for food at night (quite constantly at night).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>If he doesn't find any he sends a request to the deliveryman to fill up his hut chest with food (the deliveryman will take hutLevel food to that hut).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>If there is no food in the warehouse -> player will receive the message.</p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="Builder">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Builder Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Builder is one of the most important workers for your Colony. As long as you provide the builder with all the resources he/she asks for, the builder will build
                and upgrade all of your Town buildings.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Before any building can be built, you have to craft the &quot;Builder’s Hut&quot; block in the crafting table and use your “ Building Tool” to place th building.
                Once you &quot;commit&quot; to the placement of the builder’s hut, the block will be placed and the builder will be automatically assigned (or you can manually
                assign one with the best &quot;Traits&quot; for builder if you changed this in the setting tab in the Town Hall's GUI).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" bold="true">Best Traits are: Intelligence and Strength.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" underline="true">You now officially have a Builder! CONGRATULATIONS!</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Now issue the builder the &quot;Build&quot; assignment so he can build his own Hut first. Without the builder’s hut being built, the builder cannot build any other
                buildings. He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to check the &quot;chat&quot; regularly to see what materials the builder is requesting for
                any build/upgrade.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see builder has not finished a work order and you don’t see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder’s hut and &quot;recall&quot; the
                builder and wait a bit to see what he/she needs. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there any materials that are required and he might be missing,
                they will be in red.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you can access the Builder’s hut block, right click on it for the GUI and it's options:</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Header: The Worker assigned and his Skill Level. (you level him up by assigning more build/upgrade/repair tasks. The higher the level the faster and more efficient
                he/she will be).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire/Hire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If builder gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- to create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Page 2 of the GUI shows the "Required Resources" that the Builder will need for the Build/Upgrade he is currently working on. This amount will change as he places
                the material and will show ONLY what material he still needs to place. Any materials in RED are required and he does not have.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the button:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p underline="true">A few things to consider:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>* The placement of the &quot;Builders Hut&quot;, consider having the builders hut in the middle of where you plan to have the rest of your buildings so that the
                builder has less of a distance to walk between the his Hut and the build site.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>* The builder will not start another build assignment until he/she has finished the current one. Hint: You can go to the Town Hall and click on the &quot;Work Orders&quot;
                tab and cancel the current build as well as arrange the priorities of the following build orders. If you cancel a work order, when you assign the build again, the
                builder will continue where he/she left off.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>* Any block the builder removes (dirt, wood, planks, glass, etc.) while building and/or upgrading he/she will keep it in his/her inventory or the builder might place
                it in the Builders hut chest.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>* In order for the builder to “upgrade” any building, the Builders Hut MUST be upgraded first. Then he/she will be able to upgrade any other building(s).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>* The Builder can only build other buildings UP TO his own Hut level. For Example: if HIS Hut is level 3, he can ONLY build other Huts to level 3, NOT 4 or 5. For
                that HIS Hut need to be level 4 or 5 accordingly.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="Farmer">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Farmer Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Farmer is the backbone of your food production. The farmer will cultivate the crops you assign him/her through the &quot;Field&quot; block (Scarecrow).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>To begin with you have to craft the &quot;Farmer's Hut&quot; block in the crafting table and use your Buiding Tool to place the building. Once you &quot;commit&quot;
                to the placement of the farmer's hut, the block will be placed and the farmer will be automatically assigned (or you can manually assign one with the best &quot;Traits&quot;
                for farmer if you changed this in the settings tab in the Town Hall's GUI.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" bold="true">Best Traits are: Endurance and Charisma.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" underline="true">You now officially have a Farmer! CONGRATULATIONS!</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Now you will have to issue the builder the "Build" assignment so he can build the "Farmer's Hut". He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to
                check the "chat" regularly to see what materials the builder is requesting for any build/upgrade.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Once the builder is done, you will have to determine where your farm plot(s) will be located. So the farmer can work, you have to give him/her a hoe and the
                seeds/crop you want to cultivate and craft the "Field" block (Scarecrow). Place the "Field" block in the plot and right click it to acces it's GUI. Here you can
                place the seed/crop you want for this specific field to be cultivated. The crops he currently cultivates are: Wheat, carrots, potatoes, beets and most "modded"
                crops as long as they have normal growth behaviour (Minecraft melons, pumpkins and sugarcanes are being worked on at the moment and not supported yet).
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Note: the farmer will only till and cultivate crops that are up to 5 blocks from the field block. The farm land can be delimited by placing solid blocks (non
                tillable; sand, cobblestone, wood, etc) or air blocks in the ground next to the tillable blocks. This will cause the farmer to stop cultivating the land at this
                point, even if there is still tilled and/or tillable land after that solid/air block. Plan accordingly and create your plot(s) any shape and form you want taking
                into account that for each farm plot, the farmer will only work up to 5 blocks from the field block in every direction.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>If you decide to change the seed/crop you want cultivated, just go into the "Field's" GUI and switch the seed/crop there. Remember that for the dirt to be tillable
                and hold crops, it must have a water source to keep it tilled and crops stay planted (Minecraft limits the water source to permeate up to 4 blocks from it's
                placement).
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>IMPORTANT: The farmer will take care of up to 5 "Fields", depending on the level of the "Farmer's Hut". If the Hut is only level 1, the farmer can only take care of
                1 Field, Level 2 Hut then 2 Fields, etc. When its Level 5 Hut all 5 Fields.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see builder has not finished a work order and you don’t see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder’s hut and &quot;recall&quot; the
                builder and wait a bit to see what he/she needs. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there any materials that are required and he might be missing,
                they will be in red.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you can access the Farmer’s hut block, right click on it for the GUI and it's options:</p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Header: The Worker assigned and his Skill Level. (he/she levels up by working, so assigning more farm plots to cultivate means more work, faster leveling up. The
                higher the level the faster and more efficient he/she will be).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire/Hire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If Farmer gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- to create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Page 2 of the GUI shows the &quot;Fields&quot; that are avaialble (recognizable with a &quot;Field&quot; block placed and seed/crop in his GUI) and that can be
                assigned to this specific farmer.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the button:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>- Automatic.- By default. Here you can define if you want to "manually" assign the "Fields" to this farmer.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="Lumberjack">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Lumberjack Information</p>
            <p></p>>
            <p>The Lumberjack will harvest trees to provide the wood for all your Town's needs. He will look for nearby trees and chop them down. He will also plant a sapling in
                it's place again of the same variety he just chopped down (provided that he/she has saplings). He will only plant a sapling AFTER chopping down a tree, if there are
                no trees nearby, he will NOT plant any saplings to create a tree
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Lumberjack will search 50 blocks from his Hut for a tree, if non are found he will search in another 50 blocks, etc. up to the Town's limit.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you want The Lumberjack to NOT chop down a specific tree, replace the bottom dirt block with a cobblestone block. He will NOT harvest any tree that has a
                cobblestone block at it's base.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Before you choose a place to build his hut, take into account that he has to be near trees or that you personally will have to plant trees close to his hut so he can
                work. After you have selected a place for the hut you have to craft the Lumberjack's Hut block in the crafting table and use your Buiding Tool to place the
                building. Once you "commit" to the placement of the Lumberjack's Hut, the block will be placed and the Lumberjack will be automatically assigned (or you can
                manually assign one with the best " Traits" for Lumberjack if you changed this in the setting tab in the Town Hall's GUI.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" bold="true">Best Traits are: Strength and Charisma.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" underline="true">You now officially have a Lumberjack! CONGRATULATIONS!</p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Now you can give the Lumberjack an axe and he/she will start to look for trees to chop down right away. You will have to issue the builder the "Build" assignment so
                he can build the "Lumberjack's Hut". He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to check the "chat" section of Minecraft regularly to see what
                materials the builder is requesting for any build/upgrade.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Once the builder is done, you can think about upgrading the Lumberjack’s hut to expand the range at whcih he/she looks for trees.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see builder has not finished building/upgrading your Lumberjack's hut and you don’t see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder’s hut
                and &quot;recall&quot; the builder and wait a bit to see what he/she needs. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there any materials that are
                required and he might be missing, they will be in red.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Now you can access the Lumberjack's Hut block (right click on it) and you will see a GUI with different options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Worker assigned and his/her Level. (the Worker levels up in time by doing his/her work. The higher the level the faster and more efficient he/she will be).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire/Hire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If builder gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- to create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: You can give the Lumberjack an enchanted axe and reap the benefits of the speed he will be chopping down trees for your Town's needs. Also you can remove any
                trees/saplings and replant any type of sapling in any pattern or shape you need to create your perfect grove, for easier access and less walking around, which means
                more chop chop... ;p
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="Miner">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Miner Information</p>
            <p></p>>
            <p>The Miner will dig and create mineshafts, collect; cobblestone, granite, diorite, andesite, dirt, sand, sandstone, etc. as well as all the ORES the miner comes
                across. Important for all the Towns' building needs and crafting tools and weapons for your workers. Any additional modded blocks will also be picked up by the
                miner.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>To begin with you have to craft the "Miner's Hut" block in the crafting table and use your Buiding Tool to place the building. Once you "commit" to the placement of
                the Miner's hut, the block will be placed and the Miner will be automatically assigned (or you can manually assign one with the best &quot;Traits&quot; for Miner if
                you changed this in the setting tab in the Town Hall's GUI.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" bold="true">Best Traits are: Strength and Endurance.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p align="center" underline="true">You now officially have a Miner! CONGRATULATIONS!</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now issue the builder the "Build" assignment so he can build the "Miner's Hut". He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to check the "chat"
                regularly to see what materials the builder is requesting for any build/upgrade.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Once the builder is done give the Miner a pickaxe, a shovel, ladders, oak wood slabs, oak fences, torches and cobblestone. He will build a shaft down according to
                the level of the Miner's Hut, so if you want the best resources, be sure to upgrade the Miner's Hut and the shaft will be deeper. The miner digs a shaft down to the
                level of his hut, then he will build a network of random mineshafts branching out from the main shaft looking for ores. When he finds any ores, he will try and mine
                out the whole vein, not just what happens to be on his path.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Hint: If you see the Miner is not Working and stands by his hut's block. Check to make sure he has all the materials he needs specially: cobblestone. He might need
                lots and lots of cobblestone to fill in caves/water/lava/sand/gravel that he finds along the way while making the shaft and/or mining.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Note: The miner will only mine blocks according to the level of his/her pickaxe. And will only be able to use a tool according to the level of his/her hut (check the
                Tool Level system). Therefore the miner can only mine Diamonds with an Iron or better pickaxe. When the miner finds water or lava, he/she will try and block it up
                and work his way around it. This could take him some time to do. Mining is a very dangerous profession and the miner might die from lava or being suffocated by
                Gravel or Sand. The miner will try his/her best to be safe. The miner can on occasion get confused and lost.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Use the "Recall Citizen" button in the chest GUI to instantly recall the miner to the "Miner's Hut" block if he/she gets lost or seems to not bring anything to his
                &quot;chest&quot;.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see builder has not finished building/upgrading your Miner's hut and you don’t see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder’s hut and
                &quot;recall&quot; the builder and wait a bit to see what he/she needs. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there any materials that are required
                and he might be missing, they will be in red.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you can access the Miner's Hut block (right click on it) and you will see a GUI with different options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Worker assigned and his Skill Level. (he/she levels up by working. The higher the level the faster and more efficient he/she will be).</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire/Hire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If Miner gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- To create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Page 2 of the GUI. Shows the &quot;levels&quot; that are avaialble (according to the level of the Miner's Hut) and that can be assigned for the Miner to work in.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the button:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Mine Level.- Here you can assign what "level" of the mine the miner should be working in, creating his mineshafts.</p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- This is the most important button. Here you can access the buildings storage from where the "worker" takes and deposits materials, tools and
                anything he/she finds along the way (citizens will pickup anything in their path that is considered a "drop"; sapling, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="Fisherman">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Fisherman Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>As long as you provide the Fisherman with a fishing rod, the Fisherman will provide your Town with everything that can be caught; fish, salmon, pufferfish, clownfish
                as well as junk and even TREASURE!
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Before you choose a place to build his hut, take into account that he has to be near water or that you personally will have to build him a pond close to his hut so
                he can fish. After you have selected a place for the hut you have to craft the Fisherman's Hut block in the crafting table and use your Buiding Tool to place the
                building. Once you "commit" to the placement of the Fisherman's Hut, the block will be placed and the Fisherman will be automatically assigned (or you can manually
                assign one with the best &quot;Traits&quot; for Fisherman if you changed this in the setting tab in the Town Hall's GUI.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p align="center" bold="true">Best Traits are: Intelligence and Dexterity.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" underline="true">You now officially have a Fisherman! CONGRATULATIONS!</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you can give the Fisherman a fishing rod and he/she will start to fish. Also, you will have to issue the builder the "Build" assignment so he can build the
                "Fisherman's Hut". He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to check the "chat" section of Minecraft regularly to see what materials the builder
                is requesting for any build/upgrade.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see the builder has not finished building/upgrading your farmer's hut and you don't see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder's hut
                and "recall" the builder and wait a bit to see what the builder needs. Watch the Minecraft "chat" section. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there
                any materials that are required and he might be missing, they will be in red.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Note: The Fisherman will require a body of water of a minimum of 7 x 7 x 1 block deep for the Fisherman to be able to work. And it must be near his hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Once the builder is done, you can think about upgrading the Fisherman's hut to speed up the rate at which he/she can fish and acces to better chances of Treasure.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you can access the Fisherman's Hut block (right click on it) and you will see a GUI with different options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Worker assigned and his/her Level. (the Worker levels up in time by doing his/her work. The higher the level the faster and more efficient he/she will be).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire/Hire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If Fisherman gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- To create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Hint: You can give the Fisherman an enchanted fishing rod an reap the benefits of the treasures he/she will be catching for you. Also, the higher the level of the
                "Fisherman's Hut" is, the higher the level of "loot" he will be fishing out.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page id="Guard">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Guard Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>As long as you provide the Guard with a bow and/or a sword (depending on the mode), the Guard will patrol your Town day and night. Your Guard will also take and use
                any armor you place in the Guard Tower's chest or in the Guards own inventory.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Before you choose a place to build his Tower, take into account the distances among the other buildings and obstacles like water, trees, caves, mountains, lava
                sources, etc. After you have selected a place for the Tower you have to craft the Guard Hut block in the crafting table and use your Buiding Tool to place the
                building. Once you "commit" to the placement of the Guard's Hut, the block will be placed and the Guard will be automatically assigned (or you can manually assign
                one with the best " Traits" for Guard if you changed this in the setting tab in the Town Hall's GUI.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p align="center" bold="true">Best Traits are: Intelligence and Strength.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" underline="true">You now officially have a Guard! CONGRATULATIONS!</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you will have to issue the builder the "Build" assignment so he can build the "Guard's Hut". He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to check
                the "chat" regularly to see what materials the builder is requesting for any build/upgrade.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see builder has not finished a work order and you don’t see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder’s hut and &quot;recall&quot; the
                builder and wait a bit to see what he/she needs. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there any materials that are required and he might be missing,
                they will be in red.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Once the builder is done give the Guard a bow or a sword (depending on the mode he/she is set to) and the Guard will start to patrol your Town, visiting all your
                nearby worker huts. The level of the Guard's Tower will dictate how far he/she will patrol, so if you want a longer range, be sure to upgrade the Guard's Tower.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you can access the Guard's Hut block (right click on it) and you will see a GUI with different options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Worker assigned and his/her Level. (the Worker levels up in time by doing his/her work. The higher the level the faster and more efficient he/she will be).</p>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire/Hire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If builder gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- To create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Guard has 2 Guard modes you can choose from: Knight or Ranger. BUT... before you can choose any of these two modes you MUST change the "Assign the guard to job:"
                mode from Automatically to Manually.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>When the Guard is set to Knight mode, the guard will hold a sword and when set to Ranger the Guard will use a bow.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>This is "page 2" of the GUI. It shows the guard actions you can select: Knight or Ranger (FIRST you have to change the "Assign the guard to the job: to Manually to
                be able to change the guard actions). Also here you will be able to set (if "Find patrol target: Manually") the way the guard will work: Patrol / Follow / Guard.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Patrol When you select this mode you have two options:</p>
            <p indent="16">* If you set "Find patrol target: Automatically", the Guard will patrol from hut to hut and back to his Tower.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p indent="16">* If you set "Find patrol target: Manually", you can set the patrol route when you click on "Set patrol positions". Doing so will spawn a "Guard-scepter"
                in your inventory. You can right click using the Guard-scepter to set a single or multiple patrol positions for the Guard to patrol back and forth.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Follow When you select this mode the guard will follow you around wherever you go, as your personal Guard fighting along side you or defending you. If
                you leave the guard tower more than 40* GuardTower level blocks the guard will automatically return to his tower.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- When you select Guard mode you will receive a "Guard-scepter". You can right click on a block to set it as a guard point, the guard will stay in that
                area until his health is low or he has to restock, then he will go the Tower and resupply/regen health and will go back to the designated point.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Page 2 Guard Tower Hut GUI:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Knight.- By default. You can define if you want guard to be Knight or Ranger.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Automatically.- By default. You can select to be assigned Knight or Ranger automatically or Manually.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Automatically.- By default. You can define to be assigned the patrol target automatically or manually if you want to designate the target(s) for him to
                patrol.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Off.- By default. You can define if the guard will come back to the Tower on low health to recover his health.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Patrol / Follow / Guard.- here you can define how the guard will work.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- This is the most important button. Here you can access the buildings storage from where the “worker” takes and deposits materials, tools and
                anything he/she finds along the way (citizens will pickup anything in their path that is considered a "drop"; sapling, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: You can give the Guard an enchanted bow, enchanted sword and enchanted armor as well and reap the benefits of the protection he/she'll be able to provide and
                the drops the Guard will be picking up along the way.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="D-man">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Deliveryman Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Deliveryman will be running (YES!!! Running) from worker's hut to Warehouse to worker's hut. Visiting all your workers' and delivering the tools and materials
                they need as well as taking the spoils of their work from their chests to the Warehouse and keeps everything centralized.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Before you choose a place to build his Hut, take into account the distances among the other buildings and obstacles like water, trees, caves, mountains, lava
                sources, etc. Craft the Deliveryman's Hut block and use your Buiding Tool to place the Hut. Once you "commit" to the placement of the Deliveryman's Hut, the block
                will be placed and the deliveryman will be automatically assigned (or you can manually assign one with the best &quot;Traits&quot; for deliveryman if you changed
                this in the setting tab in the Town Hall's GUI.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p align="center" bold="true">Best Traits are: Intelligence and Endurance.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" underline="true">You now officially have a Deliveryman! CONGRATULATIONS!</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you will have to issue the builder the "Build" assignment so he can build the "Deliveryman's Hut". He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to
                check the "chat" regularly to see what materials the builder is requesting for any build/upgrade.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see builder has not finished a work order and you don’t see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder’s hut and &quot;recall&quot; the
                builder and wait a bit to see what he/she needs. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there any materials that are required and he might be missing,
                they will be in red.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Once the builder is done you can now hire the Deliveryman and the Deliveryman will start to run back and forth from the Warehouse to all the workers huts in your
                Town. The level of the Deliveryman's Hut will dictate how much materials/tools he/she will will carry to/from Huts - Warehouse - Huts, so if you want him/her to
                carry more materials/tools, be sure to upgrade the Deliveryman's Hut.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Also, the higher the level of the hut, the Deliveryman will move faster and faster back and forth (nice leveling perk, right?).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p underline="true">Building Level Max Stacks Carry</p>
            <p indent="32">1 1</p>
            <p indent="32">2 2</p>
            <p indent="32">3 4</p>
            <p indent="32">4 8</p>
            <p indent="32">5 - -</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Now you can access the Deliveryman's Hut block (right click on it) and you will see a GUI with different options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Worker assigned and his/her Level. (the Worker levels up in time by doing his/her work. The higher the level the faster and more efficient he/she will be).</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire/Hire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If Deliveryman gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- To create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: You MUST build the Warehouse to at least level 1 so the Deliveryman can do his work. Deliveryman will visit 1 worker's hut per trip then back to Warehouse. So,
                level up the Warehouse and build more Deliveryman huts to take care of more worker's huts at the same time and grow grow grow... faster faster faster!
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="Baker">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Baker Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Baker is another part of the your Town's "bloodline". He will craft bread and cake to provide for all your Town Workers' needs. He will be crafting bread in the
                furnace, provided that the deliveryman (or yourself) give him/her all the wheat to do it. the baker will also craft a cake if you provide him/her with the
                appropriate items required (at the moment deliveryman will not deliver the items required for crafting cakes, has to be provided by player).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Before you choose a place to build his hut, take into account the location from warehouse and/or farmer(s). After you have selected a place for the hut you have to
                craft the “Builder’s Hut” block in the crafting table and use your Buiding Tool to place the building.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Once you "commit" to the placement of the Baker's Hut, the block will be placed and the baker will be automatically assigned (or you can manually assign one with the
                best " Traits" for Baker if you changed this in the setting tab in the Town Hall's GUI.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" bold="true">Best Traits are: Intelligence and Dexterity.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p align="center" underline="true">You now officially have a Baker! CONGRATULATIONS!</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you will have a Baker so he can start crafting bread and cakes right away. You will have to issue the builder the "Build" assignment so he can build the "baker's
                Hut". He will be asking for the materials he/she needs. Make sure to check the "chat" section of Minecraft regularly to see what materials the builder is requesting
                for any build/upgrade,also you can check the page 2 of the builder's GUI to see a list of the materials that are required.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Once the builder is done, you can think about upgrading the baker’s hut so that the worker can craft more bread at a faster pace.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: If you see builder has not finished a work order and you don’t see the builder asking for any materials, go to the builder’s hut and &quot;recall&quot; the
                builder and wait a bit to see what he/she needs. You can also look in pg. 2 of the hut's GUI and see there any materials that are required and he might be missing,
                they will be in red.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Now you can access the Baker's Hut block (right click on it) and you will see a GUI with different options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Worker assigned and his/her Level. (the Worker levels up in time by doing his/her work. The higher the level the faster and more efficient he/she will be).</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Fire/Hire Worker.- If you think you know a better Citizen for the job.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Recall Worker.- If Deliveryman gets stuck or you just need to bring him to his Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- To create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>


    </chapter>

    <chapter id="Build">

        <page>
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Building Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>This is where you can find specific information about Buildings that do not have a Worker associated to it.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>There are several buildings that do not require a Worker for it, as in the case of the "Town Hall", the "Supply Ship", the "Supply Camp", the "Citizen's Hut" and the
                "Warehouse" for now. There are other buildings that are being worked on that will have some Citizen and Player interaction in the Future, like the Marketplace, the
                Tavern/Inn, and more to come.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>List of Current Buildings w/o Worker</title>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link indent="16" ref="Build:SS">* Supply Ship</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Build:SC">* Supply Camp</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Tut:TH">* Town Hall</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Build:CH">* Citizen Hut</link>
            <link indent="16" ref="Build:WH">* Warehouse</link>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="SS">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Supply Ship Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Supply Ship is one of the two options to to start playing Minecolonies. The first step is to craft the Supply Ship block.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Suppy Ship is one of two ways to obtain the Town Hall block. It is a great Supply of materials for you to start as well as a very illuminated place to live while
                you get your Town started. You have many chests, beds, bookshelves, torches, dispensers, wool, glowstone,etc etc. What else could the Ship contain... hhmmmm maybe
                some treasure as well?
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: if you can't place the Supply Ship, try block by block: to the right, left, closer of further from the water, or even directly over water, creating a walkway
                block by block).
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Placement of the Supply Ship.</title>
            <p></p>
            <p>When you place the Supply Ship it will spawn a chest that will contain the Town Hall block and the Building Tool. To place the Supply Ship, you need to have a large
                enough body of water. The Supply Ship is 32 x 11 blocks in length and width. So the recommended body of water must be at least (32 x 20). When you place the Supply
                Ship a chest will appear on the exact block you right clicked. The Chest will be directly in front of the ladder to board the Supply Ship (8 blocks from the
                boarding ladder) and the ladder is not in the middle of the Supply Ship. But please take into account the Town Hall placement as well before you place your Supply
                Ship.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#DF0000" align="center" underline="true">Once the Supply Ship is placed, you can't place another Ship or Camp in this World anymore.</p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="SC">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Supply Camp Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Supply Camp is one of the two options to to start playing Minecolonies. The first step is to craft the Supply Camp block.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Suppy Camp is one of two ways to obtain the Town Hall block. It is a great Supply of materials for you to start as well as a very illuminated place to live while
                you get your Town started. You have many chests, bed, bookshelves, torches, wool, etc etc. What else could the Camp contain... hhmmmm maybe some treasure as well?
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: if you’re not being able to place the Supply Camp, try it block by block: one to the right, left, closer of further from the area you cleared. It can not
                contain any holes or have any flowers, grass, fens, etc. Must be completely flat and clear.
            </p>
        </page>
        4

        <page>
            <title>Placement of the Supply Camp.</title>
            <p></p>
            <p>When you place the Supply Camp it will spawn a chest that will contain the Town Hall block and the Building Tool. To place the Supply Camp, you need to have a large
                enough flat, clear piece of land. The recommended flat piece of land must be at least 16 x 17 blocks in size. When you place the Supply Camp a chest will appear on
                the exact block you right clicked. But please take into account the Town Hall placement as well before you place your Supply Camp.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#DF0000" align="center" underline="true">Once the Supply Ship is placed, you can't place another Camp or Ship in this World anymore.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="CH">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Citizen Hut Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Citizen Hut is the only way for you to get more Citizen's for your Town. After you have crafted the Citizen Hut block, use your Buiding Tool to place the
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The building will virtually house your Citizens. Each level of the Citizen Hut will "house" 1 Citizen. So:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p underline="true">Building Level Citizens &quot;Housed&quot;</p>
            <p indent="32">1 1</p>
            <p indent="32">2 2</p>
            <p indent="32">3 3</p>
            <p indent="32">4 4</p>
            <p indent="32">5 5</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Note: For additional Citizens to spawn, you first have to have enough space in your Citizen Hut(s) to "house" your first 4 Citizens.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>For example:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>1 Citizen Hut level 4 = 4 Citizens... or</p>
            <p>2 Citizen Huts level 2 = 4 Citizens... or</p>
            <p>1 Citizen Hut level 1 and 1 Citizen Hut level 3 = 4 Citizens... or even</p>
            <p>4 Citizen Huts all level 1 = 4 Citizens.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can build/upgrade as you like, as long as the total building level equals 4. That will "house" your initial 4 Citizens, in any combination you want. Awesome,
                right?
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>After you have created enough space for your 4 initial Citizens, then the next level of a Citizen Hut you upgrade (or next Citizen Hut you build) will spawn the next
                Citizen. And so on.. build/upgrade as much as you like and every new build or upgrade level afterwards will "spawn" another Citizen for your Town.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p align="center">GUI for the Citizen's Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Header: It show the "level" of the Hut.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- To create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page id="WH">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Warehouse Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Warehouse is the central place to hold and retrieve ALL of your materials and tools that are made/gathered by all of your workers. It is the central storage from
                where the Deliveryman will store and retrieve everything your workers need. After you have crafted the Warehouse block, use your Buiding Tool to place the building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The building will hold ALL the materials and tools that are made/mined/harvested by all your workers. Level up the Warehouse to increase the storage capacity.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>The level of the Warehouse will determine how many Deliverymen will be able to use the warehouse at the same time. Level up the Warehouse to increase the amount of
                Deliverymen that will work in your Warehouse.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p underline="true">Building Level Max Deliverymen</p>
            <p indent="32">1 1</p>
            <p indent="32">2 2</p>
            <p indent="32">3 3</p>
            <p indent="32">4 4</p>
            <p indent="32">5 5</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Hint: You MUST build the Deliveryman Hut to at least level 1 so you can hire a Deliveryman and have him/her start to move the materials back and forth from the Huts
                - Warehouse - Huts. Only 1 Warehouse per Town will be recognized by the Deliveryman, do not place more or we can't guarantee bad side effects happening.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p align="center">GUI for the Warehouse</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Header: It shows the "level" of the building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And the buttons:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Build/Upgrade Building.- To create the build/upgrade work order for this building.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Repair Building.- So the builder can recreate the original building (at the current level) and fix any broken, missing, unwanted addons to the original
                building.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="8">- Inventory.- To access the buildings' storage where the &quot;worker&quot; takes and deposits materials, tools and anything he/she finds along the way.
                (they pickup anything in their path considered a &quot;drop&quot;; saplings, seeds, rotten flesh, bones, arrows, etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

        <page id="WP">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Waypoint System Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Waypoint System is a pathfinding tool for all Workers in Minecolonies. It is set by any building built by the Builder as a hut or some "decorations" as well.
                They can be set by the player to make the workers move around the Town more efficiently. To understand how they can be used, let's explain how this system works:
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Due to performance reasons our citizens' path using waypoints.</title>
            <p></p>
            <p>The following example compares our pathfinding in the first panel, with the standard minecraft pathfinding in the second panel, where the blue square is the starting
                point and the red sqaure the end point and each block represents 1 block in-game.
            </p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Every "X" is a block which needs to be checked if it leads to the correct path.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>In this case, our pathfinding requires less than half of the required checks.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>But, depending on the distances, our pathfinding can be up to 50 times faster than the classic one.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Additionally, it allows the player to force their citizens to follow certain paths.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>On default, all hut blocks are considered waypoints in a colony.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>As the example shown on the next page. The first image is our pathfinding method compared to the second image which is Minecraft's original pathfinding.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <image src="gbook:Comparison" tw="170" th="275"/>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Let's start with an example.</p>
            <p>In the next image, the "Builder" needs to travel to the "Sawmill".</p>
            <p>But, unfortunately, the "Sawmill" is very far away and finding a path would be costly.</p>
            <p>If there were no "Townhall" he would have to path directly to the Sawmill.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The decision if he should choose a waypoint on the way to a certain goal is simple:</p>
            <p>- Is there a waypoint closer to me than the actual goal?</p>
            <p>- Is the waypoint closer to the goal than my current position?</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>In the image, going over the waypoint might result in a longer path to walk for the builder but since the townhall is closer to the sawmill than his actual position
                and closer to his actual position than the townhall he will choose the townhall as a proxy.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <image src="gbook:ExamplePath" tw="175" th="126"/>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Besides buildings, it is also possible to place additional waypoints for the citizen.</p>
            <p>Every decoration in a folder called "WayPoint" will be recognized by the builder and added to the colony as a waypoint.</p>
            <p></p>
            <image src="gbook:More_Waypoints" tw="175" th="39"/>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>All workers follow the same behavior. But, due to the craziness in the miner tunnels, every node the miner creates works as a waypoint for the miner himself.
                Additionally, he always stores the path to the current node in a list. This way we guarantee that the miner finds his way around the maze he creates.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>NOTE: Waypoints only work 2 dimensional, workers do not recognize they level a waypoint is on (that could lead to confusions if you place waypoints underground
                etc.).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Workers choose their path through all waypoints the moment they start walking.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Nevertheless, if they notice on the way to a waypoint that they got closer to the goal than the waypoint is, they will, depending on the distance switch to direct
                pathing.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Also, they count a waypoint as passed when they're up to 5 blocks to it.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Due to the whole calculation they avoid running in circles.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>A more complex calculation is required when a range of possible waypoints are available when trying to path to a goal.</p>
            <p></p>
            <image src="gbook:Alternative Path" tw="175" th="133"/>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>The calculation to choose the next waypoint is simple:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Distance from origin to waypoint * Distance from the origin to waypoint + distance from waypoint to the target.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>That means that the distance to the first waypoint counts double the total distance, meaning that the less the distance to the next waypoint is the higher the chance
                that it will be chosen. And another waypoint will only be chosen if it is significantly closer to the target.
            </p>
        </page>

        <page id="Path">
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Path Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>For the moment there are certain blocks that the Citizens will try to use as part of their pathing system and also walk faster on when they encounter in their
                Path.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Currently it's hardcoded to:</p>
            <p>gravel, stonebrick, and grass path.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="Schem">

        <page>
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Schematics Information</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The Schematics are files containing block and entity information of a certain area a player scanned with the "Scan Tool" in-game. You can use the scan tool and scan
                ANY building or structure you like in SSP or even SMP and then have your builder "Build it" for you (provided that you give him all the materials needed of course).
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Once you have scanned a structure, you can use the build tool to have your builder "build it" for you.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>The first step is to make a Scan Tool:</p>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:iron_ingot"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:scepterSteel"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page id="Path">
            <p>Step Two.- Then all you have to do is right click the lower front corner (left or right makes no difference) at ground level of the structure.</p>
            <p></p>
            <image src="gbook:point1" tw="175" th="28"/>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Step Three.- Click on the top opposite corner of the structure. Leaving the entire structure inside this imaginary square. You will get a message to right click
                again to "save the schematic".
            </p>
            <image src="gbook:point2" tw="175" th="27"/>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Step Four.- Once you right click again you will get a confirmation message: "Scan successfully saved as...". That's it! Simple, fast.</p>
            <p></p>
            <image src="gbook:point3" tw="175" th="19"/>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Once you right click with the Build Tool You will have to select "My Schematics" (in the left drop down menu) and on the right side drop down menu you will see the
                scans that you have made.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>There is also a "Rename" button where you can change the name that was originally assiged to the scan (for example: SCAN_1494289342924-) to whatever you like.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can also "delete" any of your saved scans.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <image src="gbook:Schematic" tw="180" th="28"/>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="Recipe">

        <page>
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Recipes</p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Supply Ship Chest</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:boat"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:spruce_boat"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:birch_boat"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:jungle_boat"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:acacia_boat"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:supplyChestDeployer"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of boat wood type.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Supply Camp Chest</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:chest"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:chest"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:chest"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:chest"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:chest"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:supplyCampDeployer"/>
            </big_recipe>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Fisherman's Hut</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:fishing_rod"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutFisherman"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Builder's Hut</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:wooden_door"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutBuilder"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type and any door wood type.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Sawmill (Lumberjack's Hut)</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:wooden_axe"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutLumberjack"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Mine (Miner's Hut)</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:wooden_pickaxe"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutMiner"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Farmer (Farmer's Hut)</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:hoe"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutFarmer"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Field (Scarecrow)</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:hay_block"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:leather"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutField"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Citizen's Hut</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:torch"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutCitizen"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Guard Tower</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:bow"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutGuardTower" count="2"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Deliveryman (Deliveryman's Hut)</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:leather_boots"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutDeliveryman"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Warehouse</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="2"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:chest"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="4"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="5"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="0"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:planks" meta="1"/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:blockHutWareHouse"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>You can use any variation of plank type.</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Building Tool</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:cobblestone"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="structurize:sceptergold"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Scan Tool</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:iron_ingot"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:stick"/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecolonies:scepterSteel"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <title>Large Fern</title>
            <p></p>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="minecraft:tallgrass" meta="2"/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:tallgrass" meta="2"/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:double_plant" meta="3"/>
            </big_recipe>
            <p></p>
            <p>Shapeless crafting. Any two Fern in any combination.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <title></title>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="Command">

        <page>
            <p color="#0004ff" align="center" underline="true">Player Commands</p>
            <p></p>
            <title>Command line options to manage the Colonies.</title>
            <p></p>
            <p>These are all the in-game commands. The commands require elevated privileges, which means that you have to be "/OP" if you are playing in SSP or LAN mode. If you are
                in a dedicated server you must have the proper permissions in the permission system you use.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>This is the general command with all it's options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>/mc &lt;colonies | colony | citizens | rtp | backup&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>1.- /mc colonies 2.- /mc colony</p>
            <p>3.- /mc citizens 4.- /mc rtp</p>
            <p>5.- /mc backup</p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#1aa3ff" align="center">____________________________</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>The First Command will show you the list of all the Towns.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>/mc colonies list</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>And all the Town's information: the Colony ID#, the Colony Name and the Coordinates.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#1aa3ff" align="center">____________________________</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>This is the Second Command "colony" with all it's available options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>/mc colony &lt;info | delete | addOfficer | refresh | ownerchange&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">1.- /mc colony info</p>
            <p indent="16">2.- /mc colony delete</p>
            <p indent="16">3.- /mc colony addOfficer</p>
            <p indent="16">4.- /mc colony refresh</p>
            <p indent="16">5.- /mc colony ownerchange</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>The Town information can be seen using the Colony ID# or the Player name.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc colony info &lt;colony ID#&gt;</p>
            <p indent="16">/mc colony info &lt;player&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Command to Delete a Town using the Colony ID#</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc colony delete &lt;colony ID#&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Command to Add a Player as an Officer to a Town using the Colony ID# or the Player name. If none is provided it will add the player running the command.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc colony addOfficer &lt;colony ID#&gt;&lt;Player name&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Command to "refresh" the Town's information using the Colony ID#</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc colony refresh &lt;colony ID#&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Command to change the Owner of the Town using the Colony ID# and the new owner Player's name. If none is provided it will add the player running the command.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc colony ownerchange &lt;colony ID#&gt;&lt;Player name&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#1aa3ff" align="center">____________________________</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>This is the Third Command "citizens" with all it's available options:</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>/mc citizens &lt;list | kill | respawn | info&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">1.- /mc citizens list</p>
            <p indent="16">2.- /mc citizens kill</p>
            <p indent="16">3.- /mc citizens respawn</p>
            <p indent="16">4.- /mc citizens info</p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Command to list all the citizens' information from a specific Town using the Colony ID#. If none is provided it will show the citizens' information of the player
                running the command. It will show the ID# and name of the Citizen.
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc citizens list &lt;colony ID&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Command to Eliminate a Citizen from a Town using the Colony ID# and the Citizen's ID#</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc citizens kill &lt;colony ID#&gt;&lt;citzen ID#&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Command to respawn a Citizen. Requires using the Colony ID# and the Citizen ID#</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc citizens respawn &lt;colony ID#&gt;&lt;citzen ID#&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
        </page>

        <page>
            <p>Command to get the information of a Citizen. Requires using the Colony ID# and the Citizen ID#</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc citizens info &lt;colony ID#&gt;&lt;citzen ID#&gt;</p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#1aa3ff" align="center">____________________________</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>This is the Fourth Command "rtp". It will execute a random teleport, no additional options.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc rtp</p>
            <p></p>
            <p color="#1aa3ff" align="center">____________________________</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>This is the Fifth Command "backup" used to do a manual "minecolonies.dat" file backup.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p indent="16">/mc backup</p>
            <p></p>
            <p></p>
            <link ref="Welcome:Index" align="center">Back to Index</link>
        </page>
    </chapter>
</book>
